Guide to the Stanford Family Photograph Collection
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford family photograph collection
1850-1904
PC0001
Stanford family.
1.25 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
The materials are open for research.
Many photographs have been scanned and are available online here: http://purl.stanford.edu/zp252sk9657
Scope and Content
Primarily studio portraits (mounted albumen prints) of Senator Leland Stanford, Jane Lathrop Stanford, Leland Stanford Jr., Gertrude Stanford, and Elizabeth Stanford. Also included are photographs of President William Harrison with Stanford during Harrison's visit to Stanford University. Studios represented include Bradley and Rulofson, Taber, and Carleton Watkins of San Francisco; Walery of New York; and Sarony of Paris. There are also a few images taken by Leland Stanford, Jr.
Collection Contents
- Photographs
  - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, 1850-1890
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, 1850; 8279 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Photographer: Taber (SF). From original 1850 daguerotype, copied to cabinet card by Taber.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, 1860; 8763 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Photographer: Unknown
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, Undated; 8764 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Bradley and Company. Engraving by J. C. Buttre; includes signature of Stanford.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, 1869; 8268 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Photographer: William Shew (SF)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, 1869; 8269 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, 1869; 8271 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Photographer: Bradley and Rulofson (SF). Full figure, with copy print.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, 1869; 8265 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Photographer: Bradley and Rulofson (SF). Head and shoulders only.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, 1869; 8266 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Photographer: Bradley and Rulofson (SF). This is a duplicate of 8265.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, [1875]; 8767 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Photographer: Bradley and Rulofson (SF)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, [1875]; 83-128 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Photographer: Bradley and Rulofson (SF). Duplicate of 8767, less yellowed.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, [1875]; 8768 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Photographer: Bradley and Rulofson (SF). Taken at same sitting, but slightly different angle than in 8767.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, 1876; 8284a (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Photographer: C. E. Watkins (SF)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, 1876; 8284b (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, [1875]; 8769 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Photographer: Unknown. Includes Stanford's signature below image; image is similar to one by Bradley and Rulofson.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, [1875]; 8770 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Photographer: Unknown. Image same as in 8769, but includes "Hon. Leland Stanford" rather than signature below image.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, [1880]; 8771 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Photographer: Taber (SF)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, [1880]; 8772 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, [1880]; 8773 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Photographer: Sarony's (NY)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, [1880]; 8774 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Photographer: Sarony's (NY). Duplicate of 8773 and in slightly worse condition (stains).
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, [1884]; 8775 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Photographer: Elite (SF)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, [1885]; 8776 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Photographer: Taber (SF). Image fades out on bottom edge.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, [1885]; 8777 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Photographer: Taber (SF). Same image as 8776, but printed in full and slightly darker. On different card also.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, [1885]; 8778 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Photographer: Habenicht (SF). Image is identical to 8776 and 8777.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, [1885]; 8779 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Photographer: Taber (SF). Same image as 8776-8778, different board
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, [1885]; 8780 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, [1885]; 8781 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Photographer: George Prince (Wash, DC). Letter from photographer to president of LSJU, Feb. 6, 1914, regarding this image included in folder.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, Undated; 8782 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Departmental creation. Color copyprint of portrait in Museum.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, [1890]; 8783 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Photographer: C. M. Bell (Wash, DC)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, [1890]; 8784 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Bureau, Engraving and Printing. Same image as in 8781 (photo by Prince); from MEMORIAL ADDRESSES.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, [1891]; 8785 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      Photographer: Unknown. Very like the image by Prince (8781) but also shows chair and cane.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, [1890]; 8786 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Photographer: H. B. Hall's Sons (NY)
  - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, 1850-1904
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, [1850]; 8787 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Photographer: Taber (SF). Probably an 1869 cabinet card from the original 1850 daguerreotype.
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, 1869; 8788 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, [1870]; 8789 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      Photographer: Bradley and Rulofson (SF). Tinted.
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, [1870]; 8790 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      Photographer: unknown
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, [1870]; 8791 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Photographer: Sarony's (NY). "For Charlie and Libbie" written on front.
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, [1870]; 8792 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Duplicate of 8791, but no photographer's name on back and no inscription.
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, [1883]; 8793 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      Photographer: Stanford, Leland Jr. Jane Stanford in France. Quality of print and paper much like those attributed to Leland Jr. in folder 67.
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, [1883]; 8794 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      Photographer: Stanford, Leland Jr. Jane Stanford in France. Duplicate of 8793, but not the whole image. Quality of print and paper much like those attributed to Leland Jr. in folder 67.
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, [1883]; 8795 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      Photographer: Stanford, Leland Jr. Jane Stanford in France. Same people as in 8793 but different arrangement. Quality of print and paper much like those attributed to Leland Jr. in folder 67.
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, 1889; 8798 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, 1891; 8797 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, 1891; 8799 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      Photographer: Taber (SF). Same image as 8797 but on larger card.
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, 1897; 8800 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, 1897; 8801 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      Photographer: Taber (SF). Exact same image and board as 8800.
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, 1902; 8802 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      Photographer: Taber (SF). Same image as 8798 (dated 1889) but signed by Jane L. Stanford and dated Dec. 11, 1902.
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, [1900]; 8803 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      Photographer: Habernicht (SF)
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, [1900]; 8804 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, [1900]; 8805 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, 1897; 8806 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      Photographer: Taber (SF). Taken May 12, 1897; wearing brooch with likeness of Leland Stanford.
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, [1900]; 8807 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      Photographer: [Habernicht]. Sepia print, not mounted; same image as 8808-8809.
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, [1900]; 8808 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      Photographer: Habernicht
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, [1900]; 8809 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, [1900]; 8810 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      Photographer: [Habernicht]. Print made by Berton Crandall of Habernicht image [8803].
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, 1904; 8811 (Box 1, Folder 37)
      Photographer: unknown. Jane Stanford in Egypt. Postcard with note by Jane, Jan. 1, 1904; copy print of image on postcard.
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, [1904]; 8812 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      Photographer: unknown. Jane Stanford in India.
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, Undated; 8813 (Box 1, Folder 39)
      Photographer: unknown. The darbujuah used on her Nile trip. Hand-tinted black and white photo.
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, Undated; 8814 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      Photographer: unknown. Jane Stanford and friends in Egypt.
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, 1850; 8815 (Box 1, Folder 41)
      Photographer: Taber (SF). Jane and Leland Stanford. Copy print by Taber from original daguerreotype; modern copy print of daguerreotype.
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, 1873; 8820 (Box 1, Folder 42)
      Photographer: Walery (Paris). Jane and Leland Stanford.
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, 1875; 8816 (Box 1, Folder 43)
      Photographer: Bradley and Rulofson (SF). Jane and Leland Stanford, Jr.
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, [1875]; Unnumbered (Box 1, Folder 43)
      Photographer: [Bradley and Rulofson (SF)]. Jane and Leland Stanford, Jr. Berton Crandall print of image most likely taken at same sitting as 8816.
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, 1878; 8819 (2 copies) (Box 1, Folder 44)
      Photographer: Walery (Paris). Jane, Leland, and Leland Stanford, Jr.
  - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, 1868-1883
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, 8821 (Box 2, Folder 45)
      Photographer: unknown.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, 8822 (Box 2, Folder 45)
      Photographer: unknown. At age six months.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, 8823 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      Photographer: Reed & Company (Sac.). Sepia image, tinted.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, 8824 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      Photographer: Reed & Company (Sac.). Duplicate of 8823.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1870]; 8825 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      Photographer: Reed & Company (Sac.)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1871]; 8826 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1871]; 8826 dup (Box 2, Folder 47)
      Photographer: Bradley and Rulofson (SF). Caption possibly in Jane's hand: Leland De Witt Stanford aged 3 years.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1872]; 8827 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      Photographer: Reed & Company (Sacramento)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1872]; 8827 dup (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1872]; 8828 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      Photographer: Bradley and Rulofson (SF). Partially tinted.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1872]; Unnumbered (Box 2, Folder 48)
      Photographer: Bradley and Rulofson (SF). Almost identical to 8828 but cane handle at slightly different angle; not tinted.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1876]; 8829 (Box 2, Folder 49)
      Photographer: Bradley and Rulofson (SF). Caption possibly in Jane's hand: Leland Dewitt Stanford - 8 years old.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1877]; 8830 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, Undated; 8831 (Box 2, Folder 50)
      Photographer: Wood, J. M. (Albany, NY)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, Undated; 8832 (Box 2, Folder 51)
      Photographer: Wood, J. M. (Albany, NY). Duplicate of 8831.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, Undated; 8833 (Box 2, Folder 52)
      Photographer: Wood, J. M. (Albany, NY). Probably same sitting as 8831, but different pose.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, Undated; 8834 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1876]; 8835 (Box 2, Folder 53)
      Photographer: Bradley and Rulofson (SF). "Aged 8 years" on back of photo.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, Undated; 8836 (Box 2, Folder 53)
      Photographer: Houseworth's (SF)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1875]; 8837 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1875]; 8838 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1875]; 8839 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, Undated; 8840 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1876]; 8841 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1876]; 8842 (Box 2, Folder 56)
      Photographer: Bradley and Rulofson (SF). Caption possibly in Jane's hand: Leland DeWitt Stanford 8 years old.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1881]; 8843 (Box 2, Folder 57)
      Photographer: Walery (Paris)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1880]; 14060 (Box 2, Folder 57)
      Photographer: Walery (Paris). Caption on back: Leland Stanford Jr. at 12 years.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1880]; Unnumbered (Box 2, Folder 57)
      Photographer: Walery (Paris). Same image as in 14060 but not in oval (more of the image is visible).
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1880]; 8844 (Box 2, Folder 58)
      Photographer: Morse (SF)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1880]; 8845 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1880]; Unnumbered (Box 2, Folder 58)
      Photographer: Stanford, Leland Jr. Image of Leland on bike. On reverse: Plombieres, August 1880. Aged 12 years 3 months. Taken with his own camera. [old museum number 16825]
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1885]; 8847 (Box 2, Folder 59)
      Photographer: L. Alman (NY)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1885]; 8848 (Box 2, Folder 59)
      Photographer: L. Alman (NY). Duplicate of 8847.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1885]; Unnumbered (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, Undated; 8846 (Box 2, Folder 60)
      Photographer: unknown. Bears stamp of Salviati and Co. Venezia.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, Undated; 8849 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, Undated; 8849 dups (Box 2, Folder 61)
      Photographer: L. Alman (NY). 3 duplicate copies, one in bad shape.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, Undated; 8850 (Box 2, Folder 61)
      Photographer: L. Alman (NY). Tinted version of 8849.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, Undated; 8851 (Box 2, Folder 61)
      Photographer: L. Alman (NY). Duplicate of 8850.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1883]; 8852 (Box 2, Folder 62)
      Photographer: unknown. On reverse: Leland Stanford, Jr. age 15 years. Photograph from painting by Felix Clary, Paris.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1883]; 8853 (Box 2, Folder 62)
      Photographer: Hill & Yard (San Jose). Same image as 8852, slightly redder in tone.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1883]; 8854 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1883]; 8855 (Box 2, Folder 63)
      Photographer: L. Alman (NY). Possibly a proof copy of 8854.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1883]; 8856 (Box 2, Folder 64)
      Photographer: L. Alman (NY). Duplicate of 8854.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1883]; 8857 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1883]; 8858 (Box 2, Folder 64)
      Photographer: Taber (SF). Duplicate of 8854.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1883]; 8859 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1883]; Unnumbered (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, Undated; 8860 (Box 2, Folder 65)
      Photographer: unknown. Group with Leland Jr. in first row, far right.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1883]; 8861 (Box 2, Folder 65)
      Photographer: L. Alman. Leland Jr. with Herbert Nash and two women.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, [1883]; 8862 (Box 2, Folder 65)
      Photographer: L. Alman. Duplicate of 8861.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, Undated; 8863 (Box 2, Folder 66)
      Photographer: Stanford, Leland Jr. Front of a building, people on balconies.
    - Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884, Undated; 8864 (Box 2, Folder 66)
      Photographer: Stanford, Leland Jr. Travel scene? - canopy with "TIR Tenu Par Loillier."
  - Stanford family, 1875-1891, undated
    - Stanford, Thomas Welton, Undated; 8865 (Box 3, Folder 67)
      Photographer: Batchelder and Co. (Australia). With signature.
    - Stanford family - visit of Pres. Hayes, [1880]; 8866 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Stanford family - visit of Pres. Hayes, [1880]; 8867 (Box 3, Folder 68)
      Photographer: unknown. Duplicate of 8866. People identified on back of photo.
    - Stanford family - visit of Pres. Hayes, [1880]; 8868 (Box 3, Folder 68)
      Photographer: unknown. Duplicate of 8866.
    - Stanford family - visit of Pres. Hayes, [1880]; 8869 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Stanford family - visit of Pres. Hayes, [1880]; 8870 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Stanford family - Presidential luncheon, 1891; 8871 (Box 3, Folder 69)
      Photographer: unknown. Pres. Harrison, Jane and Leland Stanford, and others on lawn.
    - Stanfords and Harrisons in front of Stanford home, 1891; 8872 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Stanford, Gertrude, Undated; 8877 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Stanford, Gertrude, Undated; 8878 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Stanford, Gertrude, Undated; 8879 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Stanford, Gertrude, Undated; 8880 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Stanford, Elizabeth (Leland's mother), Undated; 8881 (Box 3, Folder 72)
      Photographer: Bradley and Rulofson
    - Stanford, Elizabeth (Leland's mother), Undated; 8882 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Stanford, Elizabeth (Leland's mother), Undated; 8883 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Stanford, Elizabeth (Leland's mother), Undated; 8884 (Box 3, Folder 72)
      Photographer: Bradley and Rulofson. Same image as 8881 but differently mounted.
    - Stanford family (Gertrude's ?) in Yosemite, [1877]; 8818 (Box 3, Folder 73)
      Photographr: Walker and Fargerstein (Yosemite). Stereograph.
    - Stanford family (Gertrude's ?) in Yosemite, [1877]; unnumbered (Box 3, Folder 73)
      Photographer: Walker and Fargerstein (Yosemite). Duplicate of 8818.
    - Lathrop, Anna Maria, [1880]; 8796 (Box 3, Folder 74)
      Photographer: Stanford, Leland Jr.
    - Lathrop, Anna Maria, [1880]; 14120 (Box 3, Folder 74)
      Photographer: Stanford, Leland Jr. Note on back possibly in Jane's hand: Miss Lathrop taken by Leland Stanford, Jr.; image is dup of 8796.
    - Lathrop, Anna Maria, [1880]; 14120 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Lathrop family with Jane Stanford and Leland Jr., [1875]; 8817 (Box 3, Folder 75)
      Photographer: Baker and Record (Saratoga Spgs). Stereograph; other people not identified.
  - Daguerreotypes
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, 1850 (Box 1)
      Damaged and repair attempted in 1906 per note by H. C. Peterson. Scalloped metal frame, copper-colored; no case.
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, 1850 (Box 1)
      with case. Old museum #18188.
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, 1850 (Box 1)
      dress with plaid skirt. Metal frame, no case.
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, 1850 (Box 1)
      with case. Old museum #18169
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, 1850 (Box 1)
      no case top. Old museum #18183.
    - Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905, 1850 (Box 1)
      in case. Old museum #18185.
    - Josiah Stanford, Sr., ca. 1850, in case. Old museum #18184 (Box 1)
    - unidentified woman, ca. 1850, partial case. Old museum #18179 (Box 1)
    - Leland Stanford, ca. 1850, partial case. Old museum #18186 (Box 1)
    - Tintype of Leland Stanford Lathrop (wearing hat), no date noted (Box 1)
    - Tintype of Leland Stanford Lathrop (not wearing hat), no date noted (Box 1)
    - Lathrop, Henry (uncased) (Box 1)
    - Ambrotype of Lathrop family ["Mrs. Stanford’s sister and her two brothers Henry and Charles"] (uncased). Old museum #18173 (Box 1)
    - Ariel Lathrop with 2 other men, one of whom may be T. W. Stanford (uncased). Old museum #18168 (Box 1)
    - Lathrop woman [Anna Lathrop Hewes?] (uncased with cracked cover plate) (Box 1)
    - Ambrotype of unnamed woman, possibly Jane Lathrop Stanford, in metallic frame (copper?) (Box 1)
    - Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893, 1848 (Box 1)
      metal frame, no case
    - Helen M. Allyne "your grandmother," tooled leather case (Box 1)
    - Josiah W. Allyne "uncle," tooled leather case, green lining (Box 1)
    - Josiah W. Allyne "uncle," tooled leather case, red lining (Box 1)
    - Helen M. Allyne (left) and Isabelle Allyne (right), sisters (2 daguerreotypes in one case) (Box 1)
    - Sophronia W. Allyne (Aunt Fronie), tooled leather case (Box 1)
    - (Allyne family) of Baby Gertrude Fronie "we think" (Box 1)
    - (Allyne family) of unidentified child: 2 daguerreotypes in 2 cases (Box 1)
    - (Allyne family) of unidentified woman (Box 1)